Let's keep going with our project to equip our LM with a tool.
LM에 도구를 장착하기 위한 프로젝트를 계속하죠
We just created this piece of code to describe our function, which I'll now execute.
우리 함수를 설명하기 위해 이 코드를 만들었죠 이제 실행할게요
And then the next step is we just create something called tools, which now has a single it's a it's
다음 단계는 도구라는 걸 만드는 겁니다 도구 목록이죠
And in our case we only have one.
우리는 한 마리밖에 없어요
It's one element type is function.
한 가지 요소 유형은 함수예요
And the function is this thing right here.
함수는 바로 이거예요
So that is now in a list that's called tools.
그게 도구 목록에 있어요
And now the moment it's time to give an LM in our case GPT.
이제 LM을 줄 차례입니다 GPT를요
For many the power to use this tool.
많은 사람이 이 도구를 사용하죠
How is that going to work.
어떻게 그럴 수 있죠?
So it's a bit fiddly I gotta warn you, be be mentally prepared for something a bit fiddly.
비트 박스를 만드는 건 좀 성가신 일이에요 미리 경고하는데 성가신 일에 대비하세요
It starts with something that will look very familiar to you.
아주 친숙한 것부터 시작하죠
This is our usual chat function.
이건 일반적인 채팅 함수예요
You know it well.
잘 아시네요
It has a message in history that you know and then it uses that to craft the messages that go to OpenAI.
여러분이 아는 역사적 메시지를 오픈AI로 보내는 데 사용하죠
Now there is a small, subtle difference here.
미묘한 차이가 있어요
Something has changed.
뭔가 변했어요
Something has been added.
뭔가 추가됐어요
I'm going to wait a moment for you to spot it.
당신이 알아차릴 때까지 잠시 기다릴게요
Once you've spotted it, it's super obvious, but there is a little addition that's been slipped in
일단 눈에 띄면 아주 명확하지만 추가로 넣은 부분이 있어요
there.
직접 보셨다면 아주 좋았겠죠
If you didn't, it's very obvious.
안 했으면 뻔하죠
Here it is.
여기 있네요
We pass in the tools.
도구를 전달하죠
The API is exactly the same chat dot completions, dot create.
API는 채팅방 .완성 .Create와 정확히 동일해요
We give it a model, we give it the messages and then we also give it the tools.
모델과 메시지를 주고 도구도 주죠
In other words, we give it this object right here.
즉, 이 객체를 여기에 주는 거죠
Uh, and when ChatGPT sorry when chat when OpenAI is taking that and building the prompt, the tokens
챗GPT, 아니 오픈AI가 프롬프트를 구축할 때 전송되는 토큰은 GPT
that get sent to the to the LLM, to the GPT four LLM, it's going to take this and convert it into
4개 LLM으로 전송됩니다 이 토큰을 토큰 시리즈로 변환해서
a series of tokens that are going to describe our function.
함수를 설명하죠
It's going to use this English to say what it does, and it's going to inform the LLM that this is a
이 영어를 사용해 뭘 하는지 말할 거예요 LLM에게 이게 호출 가능한
function that it can call.
함수라는 걸 알려주죠
Uh, and the reason that works is because it's been trained with lots of examples that use tokens in
그 이유는 많은 예제들과 함께 훈련되었기 때문입니다 토큰을 이용해서
that way to give the LLM that ability.
LLM에게 그 기능을 주기 위해서요
And so the some of the magic is about to be lost when you see what's going to happen next.
그래서 다음에 일어날 일을 보면 마법 같은 일이 사라지게 되죠
What comes back from the LLM you remember is in response choices zero.
기억하시는 LLM에서 돌아온 건 응답 선택에서 0이죠
And what we do is we find out whether or not the finish reason is this thing tool calls.
그 최종 이유가 이 도구 호출인지 아닌지 알아내는 거죠
That happens when GPT four is telling us, I don't have an answer for you yet.
GPT 4가 알려 줄 때 발생하는 현상이죠 아직 답은 못 드렸어요
Instead, I'm going to stop because I want you to call one of your tools and provide me with its output.
대신에, 멈추겠습니다 여러분이 가진 도구 중 하나를 호출해 결과물을 제공해 주세요
So if that happens, what we then need to do is collect the message from GPT four.
그런 일이 발생하면 GPT 4로부터 메시지를 수집해야 하죠
So this collects that response choice zero dot message.
응답 선택 .Message가 수집되죠
It contains the whatever it's sent back, which will in fact be a request for us to run a tool.
보내진 게 뭐든 포함하고 있어요 도구를 실행해 달라는 요청이 되겠죠
And then there's a bit of work to do to unpack that message.
그 비트를 다시 풀려면 할 일이 좀 있어요
Figure out what it wants to do and do it.
뭘 원하는지 알아내서 행동으로 옮기죠
And I've put all of that in a separate function.
모든 걸 별도의 함수에 넣었어요 Put
I've cheated.
속임수를 썼어요
I could put it all in here, but it becomes quite messy.
여기에다 다 넣으면은 좀 많이 지저분해지거든요, Put it up
So instead I've separated that out.
그래서 그걸 분리했어요
So at this point we'll see it in a second.
이제 곧 보게 될 거예요
Believe me that this function will unpack the message back from GPT four zero and if necessary, well,
이 함수는 GPT 40으로부터 메시지를 풀어낼 겁니다 필요하다면 필요할
it will be necessary.
거고요
It will call our tool and it will return the result of that tool.
도구를 호출하고 그 도구의 결과를 반환하죠
The response to go back to GPT four zero and the city that was called, uh, what we then do is we have
GPT 40으로 돌아가거나 도시로 가면 메시지
to add two more rows to our list of messages.
목록에 두 행을 추가해야 해요
Our messages, you remember, have like user assistant, user assistant.
우리 메시지에 사용자 비서가 있는 걸 기억하세요
We're now going to add two new rows.
이제 두 개의 새로운 행을 추가할 거예요
One of those rows is this thing message, which is nothing more than what we got back from GPT four
그 중 하나는 메시지입니다 도구를 호출하라는 GPT 40에서 받은
zero asking us to call a tool.
것 그 이상은 아니죠
So the first thing we add in is the assistant asking us to run a tool.
가장 먼저 추가할 것은 도구를 실행하라는 보조예요
We put that in the list of messages, and then after that, what we put next in the list of messages
그걸 메시지 목록에 넣고 그 다음에 입력할 것은 함수를
is our result of calling the function.
호출한 결과예요.
So what's now in this list of messages is user assistant, user assistant, user assistant says run
이 메시지 목록에 있는 건 사용자 비서가 실행 도구를 명령한다는
tool.
거죠
We say this is the tool result.
이게 도구 결과예요
And then that is what we're now sending back to OpenAI.
이제 오픈AI로 다시 보낼 거예요
I hope that made sense.
이해하셨길 바라요
If not, you simply put some print statements in here when you run it and you'll see it's exactly what
아니라면, print문을 여기에 넣으면 됩니다 실행할 때 제가 말한 그대로죠
I said.
메시지를 인쇄해 보면 더 명확해질 거예요
You'll see that full exchange appearing in those messages.
그 모든 게 메시지에 나타나죠
And then at the end here, as usual, we just return the ultimate answer from the LM.
그리고 마지막에 늘 그렇듯 달 착륙선에서 최종 답변이 오죠
Uh, what I should point out probably is that I've decided I don't pass in the tools a second time,
이 말씀을 드려야 할 것 같은데 저는 도구를 두 번 전달하지 않기로 결정했습니다 왜냐하면 우리
because we wouldn't expect it to run our tool twice, but there'd be no harm in putting it in there.
도구를 두 번 실행할 수는 없으니까요 하지만 저기에 넣는다고 해가 될 것은 없죠
But it obviously wouldn't use it, So the final missing ingredient, of course, is that I now have
하지만 사용하진 않을 겁니다 마지막 비트는 여기에 함수를 써야 한다는
to write this function here, which is again a little bit more involved than than one might like it,
거죠 이건 다른 사람보다 좀 더 복잡하지만 여러분 프로젝트에서
but you can just use it verbatim in your own projects.
그대로 사용할 수 있어요
It's just some stuff to know.
그냥 알아두면 좋을 것 같아서요
Um, so we've got this, this thing, this message that's come back from GPT four.
GPT 4에서 메시지가 왔어요 네
And what we have to do is unpack it to find out which tool was it wanting to call.
이제 패키지를 풀어서 어떤 툴을 호출하려는지 알아보죠
Now, in our case, we know what tool it wants to call because we only have one tool and it's the tool
우리는 어떤 도구를 호출하는지 압니다. 왜냐하면 우리는 하나의 도구만 가지고 있고 가격을 get get
to get prices.
할 수 있기 때문이죠.
Um, but I'm keeping this in here anyway so that you can see how it works.
어떻게 작동하는지 보여드리려고 여기 넣어뒀어요
Um, and what we should really do here is say if tool call equals, uh, get ticket price, then.
여기서 해야 할 건 도구 호출이 get 티켓 가격과 같으면 이렇게 하는 거죠
So there should really be a sort of like, like if or some sort of, uh, a series of, uh, like a,
그러니까 만약이나 일종의 일련의 스위치가 있어야 해요
like a, like a switch of all the possible, uh, things that it could ask to, to call.
가능한 모든 호출을 요청할 수 있는 스위치요
But in our case, we know there's only one tool available.
하지만 이 경우엔 도구가 하나뿐이죠
So that's what it is.
그런 거였군요
What we can then do is load the arguments that it wants to call.
그럼 호출하고자 하는 인수를 로드할 수 있어요
So in this this tool call there is a tool called dot function.
이 도구 호출에는 . 함수라는 도구가 있어요
Dot arguments that tells us what parameters it's chosen.
.인수는 어떤 매개 변수를 선택했는지 말해주죠
Um, and that comes back in the form of JSON.
JSON 형태로 다시 나타나요
Uh, just a string.
문자열 하나면 돼요
So we have to use the Json.loads Loadstring function to convert that into a dictionary.
Json을 사용해야 해요 사전을 변환하기 위해 Loadstring 함수를 로드해요
And then we look up the only actual argument that we have, which is destination city.
그리고 우리의 유일한 논점을 찾아냅니다 바로 목적지 도시예요
We look that up and put that in a variable city.
그걸 찾아 변수 도시에 Put it 했어요
So we have now unpacked the tool and the argument.
이제 도구와 인수를 풀었는데요
And what remains to be done is this line here.
이제 남은 건 이 선이에요
And that line obviously is nothing very clever.
저 대사는 별로 기발하지 않아요
That line is quite simply calling our get ticket price function.
이 라인은 get 티켓 가격 함수를 호출하고 있어요
We've established that's the tool it wants to run, and we've plucked out the city and we now call that
실행할 수 있는 도구로 설정했습니다 도시를 뽑고 함수를 호출하죠
Um, we then build a response.
그리고 대응을 구축하죠
And here is the response.
이게 그 대답이에요
This is the thing that's going to get shoved at the bottom of the the messages.
Get it은 메시지 맨 밑에 놓이게 돼요
There it goes.
됐어요
It's going to get shoved in there and what their response looked like is this.
Get이 그 안에 박히면 이런 반응을 보이죠
Now, you know, each of these rows has a role and content.
각 행은 역할과 콘텐츠를 가지고 있어요
And in the past we've seen that role can be user or it can be system user or assistant system user assistant,
과거에는 그 역할이 사용자일 수도 있고 시스템 사용자일 수도 있고 비서가 될 수도 있었죠 시스템 사용자 비서요
user assistant.
사용자 비서요
Well, there's something else it can be too.
다른 방법도 있어요
It can be this word tool.
이 툴이 되겠죠
So in this case we put into the response tool.
이 경우엔 응답 도구에 입력했어요
And for the content we put in a string which is this.
문자열에 입력한 콘텐츠는 이거예요 Put
This dictionary turned into a string using the JSON dump string function.
이 사전은 JSON 덤프 문자열 함수를 이용해 문자열로 변했어요
So we put in the destination city and the price.
그래서 목적지 도시와 가격을 입력했어요. TUT D.
We do also need to add this tool call ID into the the message, which is a way that it links this response
이 도구 호출 ID도 메시지에 추가해야 합니다 이 응답을 바로 전에 온 요청에
to the request that came right before it.
링크하는 방법이죠
So we're putting message.tool.id into this guy so that when it sees these two, it fully understands
메시지를 넣는군요 도구요 id를 입력해 이 둘을 볼 때 이 요청과
that that is associated with this request.
관련 있다는 걸 완전히 이해하게 되죠
And that's all there is to it.
그게 다인 거죠
Although this time This time it was a fair amount.
하지만 이번에는 양이 꽤 많았어요
There's quite a lot to take on board there.
배울 게 많아요
But as I say, step through it, put some print statements, see that working.
하지만 앞서 말했듯이 print문을 넣으면 작동하죠
But let's see now what happens if we bring this up in a chat.
채팅방에서 이걸 꺼내면 어떻게 되는지 보죠
Hi there.
안녕하세요
How can I assist you today?
무엇을 도와드릴까요?
I'd like to go to London.
런던에 가고 싶어요
Sure.
네
Would you like to know the price?
얼마인지 알고 싶어요?
The ticket price for a return trip to London is $7.99.
런던 왕복 비행기 표는 7달러예요 99살요
So it got the right price.
가격도 적당했고요
So what we're hoping is if we turn back to our Jupyter lab, what we should see is that it's printed
이제 주피터 실험실로 돌아가면 우리가 만든 도구의 이름이
that our tool was called, uh.
인쇄된 걸 볼 수 있을 거예요
And I think we can be pretty confident that it will, but let's have a look.
그렇게 될 거라고 확신하지만 한번 보죠
It is indeed tool get ticket price called for London.
툴 get 푯값으로 런던에 가야 해요
Let's keep going.
계속하죠
Uh, and how about, uh, Paris?
파리는 어때요?
899 and Tokyo.
899와 도쿄요
The ticket price for a return trip to Tokyo is 1400.
도쿄까지 왕복 티켓은 1,400페소예요
And Berlin.
베를린도요
Berlin was the one we just added in.
베를린은 우리가 추가한 거예요
Let's see if it's got that.
그게 있는지 보죠
Yes, 499.
네, 499
It certainly seems to work and timbuk2.
팀북2도 잘 작동하는 것 같고요
I'm sorry, but I don't have information on ticket prices to timbuk2.
죄송하지만 팀북2 티켓 가격은 저도 몰라요
Uh, let's have a look here.
어디 보죠
And you can see the series of tools called.
일련의 도구들이 보이죠
And we know that when it was called for Timbuk2, it would replied unknown.
팀북2를 호출했을 때 미상이라는 응답이 왔어요
And as a result, because we gave it the system prompt to say when it doesn't know, it was quite clear
그 결과 시스템 프롬프트에서 모른다는 걸 알려줬기 때문에 모른다는 게 꽤
that it didn't know.
명확했어요
And with that, there was a lot going on.
그래서 많은 일이 벌어졌죠
I hope you got a sense.
감이 있으면 좋겠네요
This is in fact, a powerful, uh, piece of functionality.
사실 이건 강력한 기능성 조각이에요
It's a powerful technique to allow you to give more powers to your LM, but but under the covers, it's
달 착륙선에 더 많은 힘을 주는 강력한 기술이지만 그 이면에는 마법이 없어요
It's really a bunch of if statements and some complicated messages to and fro, so that we can allow
정말 많은 if문과 복잡한 메시지 투 프롤로예요 그래서 LLM이 뭔가에 대한
the LLM to inform us that it needs more information about something.
더 많은 정보가 필요하다고 알려주도록 하죠
And that's how it works under the covers.
이불 속에서는 그렇게 작동해요
And I hope that makes sense to you.
그게 이해가 되셨으면 좋겠네요
And I hope you're able to use this in your own projects.
여러분의 프로젝트에서 사용할 수 있길 바라요
As ways to extend this.
확장하는 방법으로요
You can look at adding more kinds of tools and tools that might say something about the availability
더 많은 종류의 도구를 추가할 수 있습니다 비행의 가능성에 대해 말해주는
of that flight or something like that.
도구 같은 거요
So you can use more tools.
도구를 더 많이 쓸 수 있죠
Or if you want to be really bold, you can add a tool to actually book the flight.
더 대담하게 하고 싶다면 비행기 예약을 위한 도구를 추가하세요
It's a tool that, when it's called again, could just print something or could write something to a
다시 호출될 때 뭔가를 프린트하거나 파일에 뭔가를 쓰거나
file or whatever.
할 수 있는 도구죠
And that would allow the LLM to call back into your second tool and actually book a flight when the
그러면 LLM이 두 번째 도구로 호출해 사용자가 요청할 때 비행기를
user asks for it.
예약할 수 있죠
So that would be a fun one, and you'd have a bunch of arguments about the dates and the like.
그래서 재미있었겠죠 그리고 날짜 같은 걸로 많이 싸웠을 거예요
So give that a shot, and by the end of that, you will be very proficient in how to write tools and
그러니 한 번 해보시고 그게 끝날 때쯤엔 도구 작성하는 방법에 아주 능숙해지실 겁니다 소프트웨어에서
how to equip your LLM to carry out actions that run in your software.
실행되는 액션을 수행하기 위해 LLM을 장비하는 방법에도요